# JAIME RUBIO DIAZ

# AIR TRANSPORT MANAGER| DATA ANALYST

•	12/12/2000	jrubiodiaz01@qub.ac.uk	C	+34 620 65 75 32	9	Bruce Street 27. BT2 7JD, Belfast, United Kingdom
in	<u>Jaime Rubio</u>	<u>Jaime</u> Rubio/GoodReads				

Dedicated and enthusiastic, I hold a Bachelor's degree in Air Transport Operations and Management. As a Research Assistant on the CRITERIA project, I specialized in data analysis using Python. Currently pursuing a Master of Business Analytics at Queen's University Belfast, I am further honing my skills in data management, statistics, and machine learning.

Highly motivated to acquire new skills, with effective communication, and an entrepreneurial approach. I am committed to contributing to data-driven solutions and advancing my career in aviation analytics.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Research Assistant**

ETSIAE 09/2022 - 03/2023

Selected to participate in the CRITERIA project, aiming to establish mathematical models from human factors perspective of air traffic controllers, with a primary focus on data analysis using Python. Libraries such as Pandas TensorFlow, and Numpy.

#### Math and physics teacher

Acronyms Academy S.L. 09/2019 - 02/2023

Employed for 4 years in an academy helping high school students with physics and mathematics. Managing groups of 10 students and acquiring communication and leadership skills.

#### Founder

Textil Impresiones S.L. 09/2019 - 09/2022

Founded and operated a startup specializing in brand image creation for small businesses, artists, and podcasters, acquiring a diverse skill set during that entrepreneurial journey.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Queen's University Belfast**

Master of Business Analytics 09/2023 - Current

Statistics (R programming), Machine Learning Techniques (Python), Data Management (SQL), HR Analytics (Tableau), Marketing Analytics (KNIME), Data Mining, Data Driven Decision Making and AI in Business and Society

#### Universidad Nacional Educación a Distancia

Bachelor of Science, Physics 10/2023 - Current

## Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Bachelor of Science, Air Transport Operations and Management09/2018 - 03/2023

ADDITIONAL INVOLVEMENT	Member of Consulting and Entrepreneurship Society  Queen's University Belfast 09/2023 - Current					
	Member of Board of Students Representative Committee Universidad Politécnica de Madrid 09/2019 - 02/2023					
LANGUAGES	Spanish: Native speaker	English: C1,	TOEFL			

TOOLS

Pyhton: Pandas, TensorFlow
R: randomForest, TidyVerse

Power BI

SQL: Microsoft Access, MySQL
NIME

ROWS BI

Tableau OpenAl API

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

# Data Visualization for Business Intelligence Course

Platzi Certification

# **Algorithm Python Course** Platzi Certification

# API of OpenAI

Data Camp Certification

## **MY PROJECTS**

MY PORTFOLIO